建议戴上耳机
艾利之书
很好
Nice.
很好 很好 很好 很好
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
你饿吗？
You hungry?
你知道吗 你得自己过来拿 别故作深沉了
You know, you gotta come get it. Don't play hard to get.
你会喜欢的
You'll like it.
是猫肉
It's cat.
这就对了
There you go.
我不知道
I don't know what...
出去吃早餐
Leave room for breakfast.
（电池电量不足）
喂？
Hello?
求你 别伤害我
Please. Don't hurt me.
拿去 想拿什么拿什么
Here, take anything you want.
想要吃的吗？拿去吧
You want some food? Take it.
- 我不会伤害你 - 是吗？
-I'm not gonna hurt you. -Yeah?
上次那个人也是这么说的
That's what the last guy said.
你 你能帮我吗？轮子掉了
Could... Could you help me? The wheel came off.
我不会修
I can't fix it.
也许我 我要是会就好了 可我不会
Maybe if I... If I could, but I can't.
你知道么 没有香皂的唯一好处
You know, the only good thing about no soap
就是你能在一里外闻到地痞的味道
is that you can smell hijackers a mile off.
我被震撼到了！
I am impressed!
这人在３０英尺外就闻到咱的味道了
This man smelled us from 30 feet away!
该死！
Damn!
这说明咱的个人卫生咋样？
What's that say about our hygiene?
你包里装了什么？
What you got there in that pack?
什么包？
What pack?
他有枪
He got a gun.
妈的 没上子弹
Shit, it ain't loaded.
枪从不上子弹
They never are.
不是吗 伙计？
Ain't that right, old man?
打开包 把东西倒在地上 轻轻的 慢慢的
Open the pack and tip it out on the road, nice and slow.
我办不到
Can't do that.
把包他妈的拿下来 放到地上
Take off the fucking pack and put it on the ground.
要不就去死！
Or die!
你在听我说话吗？
Are you listening to me?
我在听
I am now.
- 很好 - 你在听我说话吗？
-Good. -You listening to me?
- 是 - 很好
-Yeah. -Good.
再碰我一下 你就别想要那只手了
Put that hand on me again, you won't get it back.
你们他妈的信他的吗？
Do you believe this fucking guy?
好吧 你想玩儿硬的
All right, you wanna do it the hard way.
你在干什么？
How'd you do that?
他刚把我手切掉了！
He just cut my hand off!
你们还站着干什么？亲他！
What are you standing around for? Kiss him!
他说什么？
What did he say?
他被吓到了
He's in shock.
我猜他是想说“杀了他”
I think he meant "Kill him."
我感觉不到我的手了 我的手
I can't feel my hand. My hand.
我说了你别想要那只手了
I told you you weren't gonna get that back.
是 你是说过
Yeah, you did.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你的水呢？
Where's your water?
他们没水 他们是要抢你的水
They don't have none. They were gonna take yours.
然后再把你吃了 真的
And then eat you. It's true.
在车里
It's in the cart.
你不拿走吗？
You're not taking it?
- 你要去哪儿？ - 西方
-Where are you going? -West.
- 我能跟你去吗？ - 不行
-Can I come with you? -No.
但是
But...
咱们去找今晚住的地方
We'll find shelter for tonight.
我的腿还是疼
My legs still hurt.
上帝呀
God.
不！不要！
No! No!
- 打得漂亮！ - 迈克！不！
-Nice shot! -Mike! No!
- 不！ - 抓住她了
-No! -We got her.
甜心？上这儿来！
Honey? Come here!
不 不
No, no.
- 求你 别 上帝啊 不！ - 待在路上
-Please, don't. Please, God, no! -Stay on the path.
- 住手！ - 嘿 伙计们
-Stop! -Hey, guys.
待在路上 这和你没关系
Stay on the path. It's not your concern.
不！
No!
来呀！
Come on!
待在路上 这和你没关系 待在路上 这和你没关系
Stay on the path. It's not your concern. Stay on the path. It's not your concern.
- 我不认识你 - 我知道 我不是这儿的人
-I don't know you. -I know, I'm not from around here.
不 你不是这儿的人
No shit you're not from around here.
- 好了 我不想惹麻烦 - 哦 是么
-All right, I don't want any trouble. -Oh, yeah.
好了
Okay.
我只是个顾客 明白吗？
I'm just a customer. Okay?
明白
Okay.
对不起 我得看看你的手
I'm sorry, I gotta see the hands.
我不是他们一伙的
I'm not one of them.
好吧
Okay.
我要从包里拿点儿东西
I'm gonna take something out of my pack.
- 把手指从扳机上拿下来 - 好
-Take your finger off the trigger. -Yeah.
酷毕了！是魅影９００ 伙计
Sweet! That's a Fathom 900, man.
是吗？
Is it?
我９０年代起就没见过这个型号了
I haven't seen one of those since the '90s.
是啊 我在东方的时候弄到的
Yeah, I got it back east.
- 还好用吗？ - 好用 好用 就是没电了
-Still work? -Yeah. Yeah. Just need it charged.
你能帮我充电吗？给我一个 我有接线
Can you do that for me? Give me a... I got cables.
不用接线 我可以用点滴式充电器
I don't need the cables. I can put a trickle charger on it, though, for you.
好
Good.
我是说 要是你有钱的话
I mean, if you got the coin.
有啊 先生
Yes, sir.
是的 我有钱 我有点东西
Yes, I do. I got something...
- 不错 - 是美国制造
-Okay. -It's American-made.
哦 是啊 这种我有一堆
Oh, yeah. I got a whole bunch of these.
- 是吗？ - 是呀
-Do you? -Yeah.
润唇膏呢？你有润唇膏吗？
How about ChapStick? You got any ChapStick?
没有润唇膏 没有 可我有猫油 新鲜猫油
No ChapStick, no. I got cat oil. Fresh cat oil.
- 不 不要 - 很好的 对于
-No, no. -It's good, it's good for the...
- 不 不要 - 一样用的
-No, no. -Works the same way.
那玩具呢？你有玩具吗？
What about toys? You got any toys?
我 我不玩 等等 我有个
No, I don't play... Oh, I got...
- 哦 是了 对了 对了 - 我们的鸡做得不错
-Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah. -We do chicken right.
- 是啊 好得让你直唆手指 - 对 对 对 好得
-Eh, finger lickin' good. -Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
好 好 好
All right, all right, all right.
好了 这个 再加上这些
All right, now this, with these.
当然 这些都是你的
Absolutely, those are yours.
好嘞 给我几小时时间
Okay. Give me a couple of hours.
- 帮你充上电 - 谢谢
-Charge it up for you. -Thank you.
你可以在街对面等 在奥菲安
You can wait over there across the street, at the Orpheum.
不了 我在这儿等
No, I'll wait here.
- 酒吧已经快开门了 - 我就在这儿等
-Bar is about ready to open. -I'll wait here.
你不信任我 是吧？
You don't trust me, do you?
- 我就在这儿等 - 好吧
-I'll wait here. -All right.
卡耐基
Carnegie.
一个路上分队刚开进城了 他们给你带了点儿东西
One of the road crews just pulled into town. They've got something for you.
是书吗？
Books?
一整包书
Whole bag of them.
告诉他们我现在就要见他们
Tell them I wanna see them right now.
- 留下 - 没问题
-Stay. -No problem.
来吧 咱们走
Come on, let's go.
我们干得不错
We did good.
里面没有你要的那本？
The one you want, it ain't there?
没有
No.
我就搞不明白了 这里他妈的一堆书啊
I just don't understand. That's a shitload of books.
你不用搞明白
You don't have to understand.
我明白就好 把这些让我来处理 咱们就是朋友
I understand. Leave that to me and we can be friends.
我对你有信心 你会找到它的
I have faith in you. You'll find it.
等等 我还弄到这个
Wait. I got this, too.
这可是个好东西
Now, this is a treat.
- 是香波 - 是吗？
-That's shampoo. -Yeah?
好好喝两杯去吧
Go get slammed.
找几个女人
Get some pussy.
都算我账上 你和兄弟们爱花多少都行
Everything on me, as much as you and your boys can stand.
然后重新上路
Then go back on the road.
我们会帮你找到书的
And we'll get you your book.
对此我毫不怀疑
Of that I have no doubt.
你派出去找书的人连大字都不识一个
You're sending guys out who can't even read to look for one book.
难怪他们什么都找不到
Well, no wonder they never find anything.
是啊 我就用手边的工具
Yeah, I use the tools I have at hand.
除非你愿意和他们一块儿去？
Unless you'd like to go with them?
这些怎么办？
What about these?
烧了吧
Burn them.
街对面的这家 他们有水吗？
This place across the street, they got any water?
有啊 要是你付钱的话
Yeah, if you can pay for it.
给
Here.
问问这个
Smell this.
一支路上小分队弄来的
One of the road crews found it.
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
这可能是地球上最后的香波了
It may be the last shampoo on the planet.
而它是属于你的
And it's yours.
他们找到你要的书了吗？
Did they find your book?
没有
No.
外地人？
Outlander?
让我想想
Let me see.
- 好吧 你要什么？ - 水
-All right, what'll it be? -Water.
那可是好东西
That's the good stuff.
我得从自己的配额里拿出来卖给你 所以不便宜
I've gotta eat into my own ration to sell it, so it don't come cheap.
好
Right.
再加一倍就给你
Get you maybe halfway.
索拉拉！
Solara!
拿着这个把它装满水
Take this and get it filled.
等等 你需要这个
Wait. You need this.
能请你让一下吗？
Can you please move?
谢谢
Thank you.
那是我的猫
That was my cat.
品种很不错
Fine specimen.
我看到你把它推到吧台下面去了
I saw you knock him off the bar.
不 我只是吓吓它 我没真的推它
No. I kind of shooed him, I didn't really knock him.
你朝他抬手了
You raised your hand at him.
不会再这样了 我向你保证
Won't happen again, I promise you.
嘿 马兹 再来一杯怎样？
Hey, Martz, how about another drink?
那猫上这儿来已经两年了
That cat's been coming in here for two years.
它比你更有权力呆在这儿
It's got more right to be here than you.
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
那就太糟了 你已经
Well, that's too bad, 'cause you got...
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你杀害了路边无辜的行人
Murderer of innocent travelers on the road.
你会为此付出代价的 明白吗？
You are gonna be held to account for the things you've done, do you know that?
你明白吗？
Do you?
没事了
It's okay.
我会拿着我的东西离开这儿
I'm gonna grab my things and I'm gonna walk out of here.
- 好吧 - 好了 兄弟？
-All right. -All right, brother?
是
Yeah.
大地因你而受诅
"Cursed be the ground for our sake.
荆棘与疾黍将在我们面前出现
"Both thorns and thistles it shall bring forth for us.
我们从地中来 我们从尘土中来
"For out of the ground, we were taken. For the dust, we are.
“也必将归于尘土”
"And to the dust, we shall return."
住手！
Stop!
求你了
Please.
瑞德利治
Redridge!
Redridge.
你是谁？
And who are you?
无名鼠辈
Nobody.
我不信
I doubt that.
在我的酒吧里被杀的那些人 他们才是无名鼠辈
The men you killed in my bar, now, they were nobody.
- 但是你 - 他的手没有抖
-But you, now. -He ain't got the shakes.
- 他不是他们一伙的 - 很好
-He ain't one of them. -Good.
这是一个文明的城市 我们不吃人
This is a civilized town. We don't eat humans.
我们这儿不常见到很多从前的人 现在不常见了
We don't see too many people from before. Not anymore.
- 你看书吗？ - 每天
-Do you read? -Every day.
好 这对你很好 我也每天看
All right. Well, good for you. Me, too.
你知道吗 真有趣
You know, it's funny.
虽然我们都老了 你我这样的人 我们却是未来
As old as we are, people like you and me, we're the future.
你想怎样？
What do you want with me?
直奔主题！
Straight to the point!
我喜欢这样！
I like that!
你不仅是受过教育
You're not just educated.
我从没见过谁有这么好的身手
I never saw anyone handle themselves the way you did.
我不知道你从哪儿学来的那些 但是我肯定我用得上你
I don't know where you learned it, but I sure as hell could use it.
这个小城只是一个开始
This little town, just the beginning.
我打算对外扩建
I'm about to expand.
我需要专业人士的帮助 我可以任用你这样的人
I need expert help. I could use someone like you.
谢谢 但我真的不感兴趣
Thank you, but I'm really not interested.
替我干活的人 过得比任何行者做梦梦到的都好
Well, the people who work for me live better than any walker ever dreamed.
问问瑞德利治 问问兄弟们 随便问谁
Ask Redridge here. Ask the boys, anyone.
真正的床 热乎的饭菜 还有女人
Real beds, hot food, women.
干净的水
Clean water.
你去别的地方可能会差很多 伙计
You could do a lot worse, my friend.
谢谢你
Thank you,
但我必须去一个地方
but I got somewhere I need to be.
去哪儿？
Where?
西方
West.
西方什么都没有
There is nothing west.
别人告诉我的和你说的不一样
I've been told different.
谁告诉你的？
By who?
告诉你吧
Tell you what.
在这儿住一晚 感受一下当地的热情好客 看看自己是否喜欢
Stay the night. Try a little local hospitality, see how you like it.
咱们明早再谈
We'll talk again in the morning.
给你个忠告 行者 这不是选择
Word of advice, Walker. It's not a choice.
永远都是选择
It's always a choice.
整晚都会有人在你的房间外
There'll be someone outside your room all night
要是你有任何需要的话
if you need anything.
我什么都不需要
I don't need anything.
那可说不准
You never know.
这是给你的 一些洗漱用的水和食物
This is for you. It's some water for washing and some food.
还有些许特殊藏品 代表房主的问候
Little special reserve, too, compliments of the house.
你得把这个接过去 或者说句话 这样我才能知道你在哪
I need you to take this or say something so I can find you.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
- 你还需要我帮你拿些什么吗？ - 不 不用了 谢谢
-Can I get you anything else? -No, I'm fine. Thank you.
你失明是因为战争 还是因为战后的阳光？
Did you get blinded in the war or by the sun after?
我生来如此
I was born this way.
我想或许我是幸运的 因为当一切发生时
I think probably I'm lucky, because I was already used to being like this
我就已经习惯这样了
by the time it happened.
好吧 那么 谢谢你给我送吃的来
Right, well, thank you for the food.
不客气
You're welcome.
我喜欢你的香水
I like your perfume.
只是香波而已
It's just shampoo,
但是谢谢你
but thank you.
晚安
Good night.
我不认为他明早会改变主意
I don't think he's gonna change his mind by the morning.
他不会留下的
He's not gonna stay.
他和其他人不同
He's different than the others.
你没法让他听命于你的
You're not gonna be able to make him do what you want him to do.
谁说是听命于我？
Who said anything about me?
我会派索拉拉去
I'll send Solara.
你不能那么做
You can't do that.
是时候让她派上更大用场了
It's about time I got better use out of her.
不要那么做
Don't.
求你
Please.
求你了 不要 求你 求你
Please, don't. Please. Please.
求求你！
Please!
我能进来吗？
Can I come in?
等一分钟
Give me a minute.
已经有人送过食物和水了
Somebody already came with food and water.
需要的我都有了
I got everything I need.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about that?
这儿还真是明亮
It's really bright in here.
我叫索拉拉
I'm Solara.
是 你在楼下给我装的水
Right. You filled my canteen downstairs.
是呀 你是那个行者 不是吗？
Yeah. You're the walker, right?
是
Right.
你要是担心钱的问题 都算在房主账上了
If you're worried about paying, it's on the house.
什么钱？
Paying for what?
你干嘛不坐下来？
Why don't you take a seat?
不
No.
不 我不能走 我不能 我要是走了 他会伤害我妈妈的
No, I can't go. I can't. If I do, he'll hurt my mom.
- 谁？ - 卡耐基
-Who? -Carnegie.
他是你父亲？
He's your father?
不 不是 但我们照样都属于他
No. No, but we belong to him just the same.
听着 我可以睡地板
Look, I'll sleep on the floor.
明天你可以告诉他你过得很愉快
Tomorrow you can tell him you had a good time.
我保证我不会惹麻烦
I promise you I will be no trouble.
求你了？
Please?
骑士到象四
Knight to bishop four.
该你了
Your move.
那 你多大了？
So, how old are you?
什么？
Excuse me?
因为我很少看到你这个年纪的人上这儿来
It's just that I haven't really seen too many people your age come through here before.
自从文明毁灭
Well, it's been
已经过了３０个冬天了
30 winters since the flash.
我真的不记得了
I really don't remember.
你还记得一切是什么样子的吗？ 我是说 从前的世界
Do you remember what it was like? I mean, in the world before.
我知道
Yeah.
那 从前是什么样子的？
Well, what was it like?
人们拥有的比需要的多
People had more than they needed.
我们不知道何为珍贵
We had no idea what was precious, what wasn't.
我们丢弃了很多东西 而现在的人却为了那些东西自相残杀
We threw away things people kill each other for now.
- 真的？ - 真的
-Really? -Yeah.
你有一本书
You have a book.
- 我能看看吗？ - 不能
-Can I see it? -No, you cannot.
- 我只是 只是想看看 - 不行 我说了不行
-I just, I just wanna look at it. -No. I said no.
听着 我根本不识字！ 来吧 求你了 我只是想看看
Listen, I can't even read! Come on, please, let me just see it.
你到底怎么了？不过是本书罢了！
What is with you? lt is just a book!
这不只是一本书
It's not just a book.
- 什么意思？什么叫不只是一本书？ - 听着
-What do you mean, it's not just a book? -Look.
不许再问书的事情了 明白吗？ 不要再问了 好不好？
No more questions about the book, all right? No more questions. All right?
既然你在这儿 我想问你个问题
I got a question for you, since you're here.
我可能回答也可能不回答
Well, maybe I'll answer it and maybe I won't.
你从哪儿弄到的水？
Where do you get your water?
不能告诉你
Can't tell you that.
- 是你不能说还是你不知道？ - 哦 我知道的
-You can't tell me or you don't know? -Oh, I know.
但要是你不告诉我书的事情 我就不告诉你水的事情
But if you're not talking about the book, I'm not talking about the water.
知道吗 你这人真滑稽
You're something else, you know.
好吧 我还有个问题
All right, I got another question for you.
说吧
Right.
你饿吗？
You hungry?
这儿有很多吃的
There's a lot of food there,
我一个人吃不掉
more than I can eat.
告诉你吧
Tell you what.
我们可以分享 你知道 就像曾经老人们那样
We can share it, you know, like old people used to.
好吧
Okay.
好？
Okay?
等一分钟 等一分钟 等等 坐下
Wait a minute, wait a minute. Wait. Sit.
坐下
Sit.
这是给你的
This'll be for you.
把手给我
Give me your hands.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
相信我 把手给我
Trust me. Give me your hands.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
亲爱的主 我们感谢您赐予我们面前的食物
Dear Lord, we thank you for this meal.
感谢您赐予我们温暖的床
We thank you for a warm bed
感谢您赐予我们头顶的屋檐 使我们不致受冻
and a roof over our head on cold nights such as this.
太长了
It's been too long.
是你从那本书里看到的？
Is this from your book?
别插嘴 闭上眼睛
Don't interrupt. Close your eyes.
感谢您在这样的艰苦岁月中
We thank you for the gift of companionship
给予我们陪伴
in hard times like these.
阿门
Amen.
现在可以吃了？
Now we eat?
可以吃了
Now we eat.
早上好 索拉拉
Good morning, Solara.
昨晚过得怎样？睡得好吗？
How was your night? Did you sleep well?
我照你说的做了
I did like you said.
你当然要按我说的做
Of course you did what I said.
但是有用吗？他会留下来吗？
But did it work? Is he staying?
我们没怎么说话
We didn't do much talking.
索拉拉 亲爱的 吃点东西
Solara, honey, eat something.
妈妈 把手给我
Mom, give me your hand.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
妈妈 相信我
Mom, trust me.
亲爱的主
Dear Lord.
我们感谢您赐予我们食物
We thank you for our food.
感谢您赐予我母亲
Thank you for my mother.
感谢您赐予我们头顶的屋檐 和新的朋友
Thank you for the roof over our heads and our new friends.
还有
And...
嗯 我想就这么多
Well, I guess that's all for now.
阿门
Amen.
这是你要说的词 阿门
That's the word you're looking for. Amen.
是结束语
That's how you stop.
你还说你们没怎么说话
You said you didn't talk much.
那他看书了吗？
But did he do any reading?
- 我再问你问题 - 比尔 别
-I asked you a question. -Bill, don't.
你 给我闭嘴
You. Shut your mouth.
住手！
Stop!
你在伤害你的母亲 索拉拉
You're hurting your mother, Solara.
他说过他每天都看书的 不是吗？
He said he read every day. Did he?
住手！
Stop it!
你妈妈想让你告诉我
Your mother would like you to tell me.
我不知道！
I don't know!
好吧是的！是的！他看书了！
Yes, okay! Yes, yes, he was reading.
- 什么样的书？ - 我不知道！
-What kind of book was he reading? -I don't know!
- 我不知道！皮革封面的旧书！ - 还有呢？
-I don't know! An old leather one! -And?
我不知道 封面上画了什么东西！
I don't know, it had some kind of thing on the front of it!
- 画给我看！ - 你先放了她！
-Show me. -I need you to let her go!
画给我看！
Show me!
瑞德利治
Redridge!
妈的！他一整晚都在这儿
Shit! He was here the whole night.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
我不知道 我不
I don't... I don't...
- 我只想确保你知道 - 我懂
-I just wanna make sure that you know that... -I understand.
那里没有酸性 只是沼泽水
...there's no acid in there. That's swamp water.
没关系 只要拿掉就行了 拿掉
It doesn't matter. Just take these off. Take them off.
- 好吧 让我来 好吧 只要 - 把他们拿掉
-All right. Well, let me, all right, just... -Take them off.
- 嘿！ - 好吧 你赢了 拿掉
-Hey! -All right. You got it, coming off.
- 谢谢 - 拿掉了
-Thank you. -Coming off.
你可以告诉他们是我逼你做的 明白吗？
You can tell them I made you do it, all right?
好的
All right.
- 说一遍 - 你逼我做的
-Say it. -You made me do it.
装子弹了吗？我觉得没有
Is that thing loaded? I don't think it's loaded.
有一个方法可以检验
One way to find out.
听着 我需要那本书
Look, I need that book.
我是说 我要那本书和你
I mean, I want the book and you,
但你若要我选择 我会杀了你 然后拿那本书
but if you make me choose, I'll kill you, I'll take the book.
为什么？你为什么想要它？
Why? Why do you want it?
它伴我长大
I grew up with it.
我知道它的力量
I know its power.
如果你读它 你就有力量
And if you read it, then so do you.
这就是为什么战后它们都被焚毁了
That's why they burned them all after the war.
活着就是一种信仰
Just staying alive is an act of faith.
建造这座城镇更是一种信仰
Building this town is an even bigger act of faith,
但他们不明白这点
but they don't understand that,
他们一个都不明白
none of them.
我没有适当的词句去帮助他们 可这本书有
And I don't have the right words to help them, but the book does.
我承认
Now, I admit
为了建造此地 我曾被迫去做一些事情
that I've had to do things,
我做了很多我所不愿做的事 这点我承认
many, many things, that I hate, to build this. I confess that.
但如果我们有了那本书
But if we have that book,
我就不必再这样了
I wouldn't have to.
想象一下吧
Now imagine.
想想这个小小的世界 可以变得多么不同 多么正义
Imagine how different, how righteous this little world could be
如果我们能用正确的词句表达信仰
if we had the right words for our faith.
人们会真正明白 自己为何而生 正在做什么
The people would truly understand why they're here and what they're doing
他们不再需要任何卑劣的动机
and they wouldn't need any of the uglier motivations.
把那本书藏起来是不对的 它就是为了分享而存在的
It's not right to keep that book hidden away. It's meant to be shared with others.
它注定要被广为流传
It's meant to be spread.
这不就是你所想要的嘛？
lsn't that what you want?
我一直
With all of my heart and soul.
全心全意地相信
I always believed that
我会找到这本书的归属 找到需要它的地方
I'd find a place where this book belonged, where it was needed.
但我至今还未找到那个地方
But I haven't found it yet.
我喜欢这家伙
I love this guy.
杀了他 拜托
Shoot him, please.
你们还站着干什么？
What are you standing around for?
干掉他！见鬼！干掉他！
Take him out, God damn it! Take him out!
我不喜欢被跟踪
I don't like being followed.
我想和你一起走！
I wanna come with you!
不行
No, you don't.
我讨厌这里
I hate it here.
- 那就改变它 - 我妈妈觉得我和你一起会比较安全
-Then change it. -My mother thinks I'll be safer with you.
我会带你去我们打水的地方
I'll take you to where we get our water.
你能带多少就可以带多少
You can have all that you can carry.
我是说 我们能带多少就带多少
I mean, all that we can carry.
卡耐基知道 北边还有两处泉水
Carnegie knows about two more springs up north.
他说他还要建更多的城镇
He says he's gonna build more towns.
他是怎么知道这处泉水的？
How'd he know about this one?
他年轻的时候在这儿待过
He'd been here when he was young.
在从前的世界
In the world before.
我猜 其他知道这地方的人都已经死了
I guess everyone else who knew about it died.
咱们真的最好快点
We really better hurry.
我想我把眼镜忘在里面了 去帮我看一下 我在这儿放哨
I think I left my glasses inside. Just take a look for me. I'll look out here.
好
Okay.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你这个大骗子！
You are such a liar!
我没骗你
I'm not a liar.
你说要是找到水 我就可以跟你一起走！
You said I could come with you if you got your water!
我可没说 是你说的
I didn't say that. You said that.
再说了 大路也不适合你
Besides, the road's no place for you.
那比你想象得糟多了
It's much worse than you think.
再见了 索拉拉 认识你真好 我说真的
Goodbye, Solara. It's nice knowing you, I mean that.
- 嘿 - 什么？
-Hey. -Yeah?
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
你洗过你他妈的脏手了吗？
Have you washed your filthy fucking hands?
洗了两次 用你的肥皂
Twice. With your soap.
集结一队人 我们要跟踪他
Put a crew together. We're going after him.
就为了本破书
For a fucking book.
那不是本破书！
It's not a fucking book!
是武器！
It's a weapon!
可以击溃 脆弱与绝望之人的理智与情感的武器！
A weapon aimed right at the hearts and minds of the weak and the desperate!
它能让我们控制他们！
It will give us control of them!
如果我们不想偏安一隅 就要得到它！
If we wanna rule more than one small fucking town, we have to have it!
人们会从四面八方赶来 对我唯命是从
People will come from all over, they'll do exactly what I tell them
只要我的话是从那本书里找到的
if the words are from the book.
这事情从前就发生过 并且将再次发生
It's happened before, and it'll happen again.
那本书就是我们需要的全部
All we need is that book.
那我要索拉拉
Then I want Solara.
你是在跟我讨价还价吗？
Are you bargaining with me?
我们是在做交易吗？
Is this a deal we're making here?
我们失掉了很多人
We lost a lot of men.
你比以往更需要我
You need me more than ever.
现在 你说那本书值得大费周章 那我相信你
Now, you say that book's worth the trouble. Well, I believe you,
但是作为交换 我要索拉拉
but I want Solara for it.
为何不？为何不？
Why not? Why not?
咱们从这破地方出去吧
Let's get the fuck out of here.
待在路上 这与你无关
Stay on the path. It's not your concern. Stay on the path. It's not your concern.
我们要去哪儿？
Which way are we headed?
西方
West.
喂？
Hello?
有人能帮我吗？
Can anyone help me?
喂？有人在吗？
Hello? Is anybody there?
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
是的 我很好 你去吧 我会没事的
Yes. I'm fine. You go along. I'll be okay.
- 不 不 来吧 我来帮你 - 不了 真的不用 拜托了 我没事
-No, no, here, let me just help you. -No, really, please. I'm fine. Really.
我需要男人来帮我 不是你 你走吧
I need a man to help, not you. You just go along.
- 没关系的 一分钟就好 - 不要！没事的 拜托了
-It's okay, it'll just take a minute. -No! It's fine. Please.
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
放开我！
Get off me!
谢谢！
Thank you!
在那儿
Over there.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你听到了吗？
You hear that?
听到什么？
Hear what?
别动 别动
Don't move. Don't move.
来 把弓弦解下来
Here. Take the wire off of that.
绕起来
Spool it up.
- 这是干什么？ - 晚餐
-What is that? -Dinner.
就好像他是被什么保护着
It's like he's protected somehow,
就好像没有什么能触碰到他
like there's nothing that can touch him.
他妈的他只是个凡人罢了
He's just a fucking man.
你给他一枪 他会像其他人一样倒下
You put a bullet in him, he'll go down like any other.
还是温的
Still warm.
死了才不过几小时
No more than a few hours dead.
他走不远
He can't be far.
狗娘养的！
Son of a bitch!
索拉拉
Solara.
你确定还想要她吗？
Are you sure you still want her?
天快黑了 咱们不能晚上跟踪他们 会被发现的
It's gonna be dark soon. We can't track them at night, they'll see us coming.
我们可能会超过他们而自己还不知道
We could drive right past them and never know it.
他是对的
He's right.
他们靠步行 会累的 他们需要睡眠
They're on foot, tired. They'll have to sleep.
咱们明天把路程补回来 中午前就能赶上他们
We'll make up the ground tomorrow. We'll have them before morning's out.
最好是这样
That better be a guarantee.
你真的每天都读同一本书吗？
Do you really read the same book every day?
从不间断
Without fail.
你能读点给我听吗？
Will you read some to me?
求你了
Please?
主是我的牧人
"The Lord is my shepherd.
我不可失去他
"I shall not want.
他让我躺在绿色的草地上
"He makes me to lie down in green pastures.
将我引到安静的水源边
"Leads me beside the still waters.
他拯救我的灵魂
"He restores my soul.
他以自己的名义 引我走上正义之路
"He leadeth me in the path of righteousness, for his name's sake.
是的 即使我走过死亡的阴影与深谷
"Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death
“我不惧怕邪恶 因你与我同在”
"I will fear no evil, for thou art with me."
- 真美 - 你喜欢？
-That's beautiful. -You like that?
- 你写的？ - 是啊 我写的
-Did you write that? -Yes, I did.
真的
Really?
不 不 不是
No, no. No.
不 在你我之前很久它就存在了 这点是肯定的
No, that was around a long time before you and I got here, that's for sure.
你说它不是普通的书 这是什么意思？
What did you mean when you said it's not just any book?
它是唯一的一本
It's the only one.
真的？
Really?
战争之后 未在战火中被毁的
After the war, people made it their business
也被人们找到并被销毁
to find and destroy any that the fires didn't get already.
有人说战争本就是因此而起
Some people said this was the reason for the war in the first place.
不管怎么说 这是唯一幸存的一本了
Anyway, it's the only one that survived.
你又是怎么得到它的？
How'd you get it?
据说
They said that the war
战争在天上扯开一个洞 你可能听过这类故事
tore a hole in the sky, you've probably heard the stories.
是的
Yeah.
天被扯出了一个洞 太阳就下来了
Tore a hole in the sky, sun came down
烧毁了一切
and burned everything.
一切物 一切人
Everything and everybody.
你很幸运 躲在了这种地方 或是地下
You were lucky to hole up and hide in a place like this or underground.
但大多数人并不幸运
Most people weren't lucky.
于是 一年之后 我们开始从躲藏的地方出来
So, a year later, we started coming out,
人们四处游荡
and people wandered around.
我不知道自己要做什么 我想找个方法活下去
I, not knowing what I was gonna do, trying to find a place to survive.
一天 我听见一个声音
One day, I heard a voice.
很难解释 但那就好像
It's hard to explain, but it was like it...
就好像是从我内心发出的声音
Like it was coming from inside of me.
但我能清楚地听到它 和我现在听你说话一样清楚
But I could hear it as clear as I can hear you talking to me now.
那个声音怎么说？
What did this voice say?
它指引我去了一个地方
It led me
在那里我找到了这本书
to a place where I found the book
它被埋在瓦砾之下
buried under some rubble.
那个声音告诉我 把书带到西方去
The voice told me to carry the book out west.
它告诉我 前方的路会成为我的指引
Told me that a path would be laid out for me,
我会被指引到一个地方 使这本书安全的地方
that I'd be led to a place where the book was safe.
它告诉我 我会被护佑
Told me that I'd be protected
任何人任何事 都无法挡住我的去路
against anyone or anything that stood in my path.
自那以后我就一直沿着指引前进
I've been walking ever since.
你这么做 就因为脑袋里有一个声音让你这样？
And you did all that because a voice in your head told you to?
是的
Yes, I did.
我清楚当时我听到了什么
I know what I heard.
我也清楚现在我所听到的
I know what I hear.
我知道自己没疯
I know I'm not crazy.
我也知道 没有它的护佑 我永远不会成功
And I know I would've never made it without help.
- 那是什么？ - 这个问题不能回答
-What's that? -One question too many.
睡觉吧 明天一早就要出发
Go to bed, we got an early start in the morning.
嘿
Hey.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
- 对不起 我以为你睡着了 - 我没睡着
-I'm sorry, I thought you were sleeping. -I wasn't sleeping.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我只想看一眼那本书
I just wanted to see the book.
除了我没人能碰它 你明白吗？
Nobody touches it but me, you understand me?
你懂我的意思吗？
Do you understand me?
- 是的 我明白了 - 那就好 睡觉去
-Yes, I understand. -Good. Go to sleep.
反正你也说了自己不识字 你看了也没用
You said you don't know how to read anyway. It's no use to you.
是啊
Yeah.
所以你教我看
So teach me.
等等 等等 停下！
Hold up. Hold up! Stop!
你说你已经走了３０年 对吧？
You know, you say you've been walking for 30 years, right?
对
Right.
你有没有想过自己可能是迷路了？
Have you ever thought that maybe you were lost?
没有
Nope.
可你怎么知道自己的方向是对的？
Well, how do you know that you're walking in the right direction?
“我们靠信念走 不是视力”
"We walk by faith, not by sight."
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是你知道它是正确的 尽管还没有被证明
It means that you know something, even if you don't know something.
这话根本说不通
That doesn't make any sense.
不需要说通 这是信仰
Doesn't have to make sense, it's faith. It's faith.
是黑暗平原上的光明之花
It's the flower of light in the field of darkness
它给我前行的力量 你明白吗？
that's giving me the strength to carry on. You understand?
那是你从书上看来的吗？
Is that from your book?
不是 是约翰尼·卡什在福尔松监狱的演唱会
No, it's Johnny Cash live at Folsom Prison.
什么？
What?
- 你觉得那儿有人住吗？ - 不知道
-Do you think anyone lives there? -I don't know.
或许会有水
Maybe there's water.
呆在我身后 （标牌：禁止擅闯）
Stay behind me.
这儿真奇怪
This is weird.
你们是谁？
Who are you?
我们只是旅者 我们无意伤人
We're travelers, that's all. Don't mean any harm.
不得擅闯！你们没看到牌子吗？
No trespassing! Haven't you read the sign?
我们很抱歉 我没看到牌子
We're very sorry. I didn't see it.
你想干什么？
What's your business?
- 我们只是 - 不想干什么！
-We were just... -No business!
只是 我们很抱歉 如果您允许 我们这就离开
Just... We're very sorry, and if you let us, we'll be on our way.
乔治 看看他们 其中一个只是个姑娘
George, look at them. One of them is just a girl.
是啊 老生常谈 我听过不下百遍
Yeah. It's an old story, I've heard it a hundred times before.
如今很少有人来拜访我们了 乔治对每个人都很多疑
We get so few visitors these days. George is suspicious of everybody.
我叫玛莎 想喝点茶吗？
I'm Martha. Would you care for some tea?
听听音乐？能让人放松的
How about some music? It's so soothing.
乔治！
George!
觉得怎样？很好听吧 请喝
How do you like it? It's nice. Please.
- 好喝吗？ - 好喝 好喝 真是 味道很浓
-Is that good? -Good, good. That's... Taste is rich.
你们单靠自己能活到现在真是不易
It's amazing that you two have survived out here all by yourselves.
是这样的 乔治是个能工巧匠
Well, now, George is something of a handyman.
他在这地方设了很多机关 好让这里更安全
He did a lot of work on this place, making it safe.
我们可能老了 但很顽强
We may be old, but we're resilient.
我们知道好些想霸占这里的人
We've known more than a few who've tried to take this place from us.
- 是吧 乔治？ - 是啊
-Haven't we, George? -Yes, we have.
- 是啊 - 我给你们看点东西 来吧
-Right. -I wanna show you something. Come on.
乔治 不！不是现在！
George, no! Not now!
来吧！
Come on!
- 这些是 - 坟墓？当然
-Are these... -Graves? Sure.
不把他们埋起来是很不文明的
Be uncivilized not to bury them.
再说了 埋起来对土质也好
Besides, it's good for the soil.
回到屋里来吧 我想我可以给你们做点三明治
Come on back inside. I think I might be able to rustle you up some sandwiches.
好 谢谢 非常感谢
Well, thank you, thank you very much.
- 我们该走了 - 他们杀了那些人
-We gotta go now. -They killed all these people.
不只是杀了 他们吃了那些人
They didn't just kill them, they ate them.
- 她的手 她的手在抖 - 人肉吃太多了 咱们走
-Her hands... Her hands were shaking. -Too much human meat. Let's go.
我找到了些肉 我想你们应该饿了
I found some meat. I hope you're hungry.
不 不 谢谢
Nope. No, thank you.
那个 我们 我们该走了
Well, we... We gotta be going.
- 这么快？ - 是啊 恐怕是的
-So soon? -Yeah, I'm afraid so.
- 你确定你们不留下来吗？ - 我确定 非常确定
-Are you sure you won't stay? -I'm sure, I'm very sure.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
索拉拉 你拿着这个 替我们开下门 谢谢
Solara, you take this. Open the door for us, please.
- 索拉拉 说谢谢你们的茶 - 谢谢你们的茶
-Solara, say thank you for the tea. -Thank you for the tea.
很谢谢你们的茶
Thank you so much for the tea.
回屋里去
Go back inside.
乔治 出什么事了？
George, what's wrong?
一大帮全副武装的恶徒 就是这么回事！
Whole company of armed degenerates, that's what's wrong!
是他们把那帮人引来的
And they led them straight to us.
- 我刚摆出些好瓷器 - 去你的瓷器吧！
-I just set out the good china. -Fuck the china!
你还有其他武器吗？
Have you got any more weapons?
武器？我给你看看武器
Weapons? I'll show you some weapons.
- 你会开枪吗？ - 当然
-Can you shoot a gun? -Of course.
快来！快！
Come on, come on!
我们知道你们在里面
We know you're in there!
到外面来 没有人会受伤
Come on out and nobody needs to get hurt!
我会放你一马
I'll make it easy!
把索拉拉和书交出来！
Send out Solara with the book!
- 我们怎么办？ - 我知道自己在干什么！
-What are we gonna do? -I know what the fuck I'm doing!
- 等等 - 我只要书和姑娘
-Wait, wait, wait. -That's all I want, the book and the girl!
他们不打算出来
They ain't coming out.
妈的！趴下！所有人都趴下！
Shit! Get down! Everybody, get down!
嘿！那个你听到的声音
Hey! You know that voice you heard?
有说过这件事情吗？
Did it say anything about this?
我们会活着出去的 你我都是！
We'll get out alive, both of us!
那我们呢？
What about us?
没提到你们
Didn't mention you!
停火！
Cease fire!
玛莎？玛莎？
Martha? Martha?
玛莎！玛莎！
Martha! Martha!
- 玛莎 - 从侧面进去！
-Martha. -Go in on the side! Over on the side!
你们这帮畜生！
You bastards!
- 房子侧面！ - 你们这群畜生！
-The side of the house! -You fucking bastards!
- 停火！ - 他们在干什么？
-Hold your fire! Hold your fire! -What are they doing?
肯定不是什么好事
Nothing good.
书在哪儿？
Where's the book?
搜他的包
Check his pack.
不在这儿
It ain't here.
这是你最后的机会 交出书 不然我就把你埋在这儿
This is your last chance. You give it up or I swear I'll bury you out here.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
咱们再试一次
Let's try this again.
- 卡耐基！ - 什么？
-Carnegie! -What?
好了 书在什么地方？
Now, where's the book?
把书给他 求你了
Give him the book, please.
别告诉他
Don't tell him.
在房子里 电视机后面
It's in the house, back of the TV.
去检查电视机！
Go check the TV!
检查什么？
The what?
你他妈气死我了 你 你去！去！
You're fucking shitting me. You, go! Go!
无论什么 只要信 就必得到
Ask, and you shall receive.
神是善的 不是吗？
God is good, is he not?
一直都是
All the time.
不是一直
Not all the time.
不！不！
No! No!
看到了吗？
You see?
我怎么告诉你们的？
What did I tell you?
他只是个凡人
He's just a man.
不！别碰他！
No! Leave him alone!
求你了！住手！
Please, stop!
你的护佑呢？
Where's your protection now?
为我祈祷
Pray for me.
好吗？
Okay?
我是认真的
I mean it.
不！
No!
妈的！
Shit!
回去！
Go back!
快点！快点
Come on! Come on!
我们的油只够回去的 你要去追她吗？
We barely got enough fuel to make it back. You wanna go after her?
不去
No.
- 你去哪儿？ - 我要去西方 必须要去西方
-Where are you going? -I'm going west. Gotta go west.
嘿！
Hey!
给
Here.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
为什么？
For what?
- 都是我的错 - 不 不是你的错
-This. This is all my fault. -No, it's not.
就是我的错 我要是没跟着你 这一切都不会发生
No, it is. If I didn't come with you, none of this would've happened.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我做了自己必须做的
I did what I had to do.
我认为 任何事情都不能让你放弃那本书
I didn't think anything could make you give up that book.
我以为它很重要
I thought it was too important.
这些年我带着它 每天都读它
All the years I've been carrying it and reading it every day.
我太着眼于保护它的安全
I got so caught up with keeping it safe,
却忘记了按照从中学到的去生活
I forgot to live by what I learned from it.
好吧 那是什么呢？
Yeah, and what's that?
只是
Just...
奉献他人 多过关照自己
Do for others more than you do for yourself.
不管怎么说 这就是我从中学到的
That's what I got from it, anyway.
你闻到什么了没有？
You smell that?
- 什么？ - 在空气里
-What? -In the air?
盐？
Salt?
我们正在靠近海洋
We're getting close to the ocean.
就是这儿了
That's it.
去找工程师！
Get the Engineer!
别再靠近！
That's far enough!
你们来这儿干什么？
What's your business here?
我的名字叫艾利
My name is Eli!
我有一本英王钦定本圣经
I have a King James Bible in my possession.
呆在那里别动！
Remain where you are!
别试图有什么动作 否则就开枪！
Don't attempt to make any sudden moves, or you will be fired upon!
小心点 小心
Be careful with it. Be careful.
小心点
Careful with it.
他们没有武器
They're clean.
我们做这件事已经很久了
We've been doing this for a long time now.
- 感觉像是博物馆 - 不 可不只是博物馆
-Feels like a museum. -No, it's much more than that.
这是我们将重新开始的地方
This is where we're going to start again.
我们有一台印刷机 很快就可以投入使用
We've got a printing press. It'll be operational quite soon.
我们要让人们了解那失落的世界
We're going to teach people about the world they lost.
帮助他们开始重建
Help them start to rebuild it.
我是说 看吧 莎士比亚 大英百科全书 只差几卷不全
I mean, look. Shakespeare. Britannica, missing only a few volumes.
有一整个系列的 美妙的莫扎特和瓦格纳唱片
There's a whole series of beautiful Mozart and Wagner records
依旧完好如初
in still very pristine condition.
但从来没有圣经 至少目前为止没有
But never a Bible. Well, not until now.
那么 我能问问它是什么样子吗？
Well, may I ask what condition it's in?
很旧了
It's beat up,
不过还可以用
but it will do the job.
- 你觉得我能看看它吗？ - 是的 可以
-Do you think I could see it? -Yes, you may.
- 好了 打开了 - 你打开了！
-That's it. It's open. -You there?
你有什么东西可以写字吗？
Do you have anything to write on?
能请你给我们那些书写纸吗？
Could you get us some writing paper, please?
要很多
And a lot of it.
很多很多
A whole lot of it.
不可能
It can't be.
It...
不可能！
It's impossible!
It can't be!
集中精神 写下来
Pay close attention and write down
我说的每一句话
everything I say
每一个字
exactly as I say it.
摩西之书的第一部
"The first book of Moses.
叫做创世纪
"Called Genesis.
第一章 第一节
"Chapter one, verse one.
盲文
起初
"In the beginning,
神创造天地
"God created the heavens
"and the earth.
第二节
"Verse two.
地是空虚混沌
"And the earth was without form
"and void.
渊面黑暗
"And darkness
"was upon the face of the deep.
神的灵
"And the Spirit of God
"was hovering
"over the face of the waters.
第三节
"Verse three.
神说
"And God said,
‘要有光’
"'Let there be light.'
“就有了光”
"And there was light."
索拉拉在哪里？
Where is Solara?
在外面
Out there.
她的选择
Her choice.
我想带她回来 她拒绝
I tried to bring her back. She refused.
她拒绝后 你对她做了什么？
What did you do when she refused?
- 念出来 - 你对我女儿做了什么？
-Read it. -What did you do to my daughter?
- 念出来！ - 你对我女儿做了什么？
-Read it! -What did you do to my daughter?
你随时可以开始
You can start anytime.
对不起
I'm sorry.
太久了 我不记得了
It's been so long, I don't remember.
- 你必须记得 - 必须？真的？
-You have to. -I have to? Really?
不 不 你必须记得 求你了
No, no, no, no. You have to. Please.
你的腿
Your leg.
已经不疼了
It doesn't hurt anymore.
我能闻到
I can smell it.
你处心积虑要找那本书
You worked so hard for that book.
你付出了那么多 那么多人的生命
You sacrificed so much, so many men.
比你能承受的还多
More than you could spare.
如今 那些从前连你的名字都不敢提的人
Now all those people who were too scared to even say your name,
他们就在楼下 捣毁你的酒吧 你知道吗？
they're downstairs, tearing up the bar right now. Did you know that?
而且没有人站出来阻止他们
And there's no one there to stop them.
而你却如此狂热
And you're feverish.
无法想象那种感觉 想要的东西近在咫尺
I can't imagine what it must feel like to have what you want so close
- 却又似乎相隔天涯 - 住口！
-and it might as well be a million miles away. -Stop it!
你要离开我吗？
Are you leaving me?
克劳迪娅？
Claudia?
克劳迪娅！
Claudia!
让开！
Get away! Get away!
是我的！
It's mine!
亲爱的主
Dear Lord,
感谢你给我力量与信念
thank you for giving me the strength and the conviction
好让我完成你交付给我的使命
to complete the task you entrusted to me.
感谢你真诚的指引 让我克服道路上的诸多困难
Thank you for guiding me, straight and true, through the many obstacles in my path,
感谢你赐予我坚毅 尽管周围的一切都已迷失
and for keeping me resolute when all around seemed lost.
感谢你的保护 感谢你在道路上的诸多指引
Thank you for your protection and for your many signs along the way.
我为一切我所行的善感谢你 对我所行的恶 我忏悔
Thank you for any good that I may have done. I'm so sorry about the bad.
你不必离开的 你知道 我们很欢迎你留下
You don't have to leave, you know. You're very welcome to stay here.
- 你会很安全 - 谢谢你
-You'll be perfectly safe. -Thank you,
但这件事我必须做
but this is something that I have to do.
你要去哪儿？
Where will you go?
回家
Home.
感谢你赐予我的朋友
Thank you for the friend I made.
请保佑她 就像你曾经保佑我
Please watch over her as you've watched over me.
感谢你最终让我安息
Thank you for finally allowing me to rest.
我太累了
I'm so very tired,
但现在 我将安息
but I go now to my rest, at peace,
因为我知道 当我在世之时 我做的是对的
knowing that I have done right with my time on this earth.
我打了场漂亮的仗
I fought the good fight.
我完成了征程
I finished the race.
我守护了信仰
I kept the faith.